<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Remarks upon the navy. The second part containing a reply to the observations on the first part : with a discourse on the discipline of the navy, shewing that the abuses of the seamen are the highest violation of Magna Charta, and the rights and liberties of English men /</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 58 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 18 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A70970</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R949A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R4016</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11885616</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11885616</idno>
            <idno type="VID">50365</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A70970)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 50365)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 508:16 or 1210:33b)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Remarks upon the navy. The second part containing a reply to the observations on the first part : with a discourse on the discipline of the navy, shewing that the abuses of the seamen are the highest violation of Magna Charta, and the rights and liberties of English men /</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 30 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>This item also appears at reel 1210:33b bound following "Observations on a pamphlet" (Wing O101).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Royal Navy.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History, Naval.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:50365:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:50365:1"/>
            <p>Remarks upon the NAVY. <hi rend="blackletterType">The Second Part.</hi> CONTAINING A REPLY to the Obſervations on the Firſt Part.</p>
            <p>WITH A Diſcourſe on the DISCIPLINE of the Navy, ſhewing that the Abuſes of the Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men are the higheſt Violation of <hi>Magna Charta,</hi> and the Rights and Liberties of <hi>Engliſh</hi> Men.</p>
            <p>In a Letter from a <hi>Sailor</hi> to a Member of the Honourable <hi>Houſe of Commons.</hi>
            </p>
            <q xml:lang="lat">
               <hi>Haec niſi inde aberunt, centuplex murus rebus ſervandis parum eſt.</hi> 
               <bibl>Plaut. in Perſa.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed in the Year 1700.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:50365:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:50365:2"/>
            <head>The Second Part OF THE REMARKS on the NAVY.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>I Thank you for ſending me the Obſervations upon the firſt part of my Remarks on the Navy, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe it came while I was writing ſomething upon the Diſcipline of the Navy; ſo that at the ſame time I have an opportunity to correct the Inſolence of that inſignificant Scribler. I can aſſure you, Sir, I am as well acquainted with the Gentleman he ſcanda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lizes, as the Author himſelf is with the Secretary of the Admiralty; and tho I much prefer Argument before Reviling, I muſt ſpare a few Paragraphs in vindicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of one that bears a better Character in the world than this trifling Obſervator can pretend to. This Author ſays, that what he has ſent into the World, is the Effect of <hi>Ale</hi> and <hi>Brandy:</hi> Now I know that Gentleman never drinks one of thoſe Liquors, and very ſeldom of the other; ſo that beginning his Book with a <hi>Lye,</hi> you have little reaſon to believe him after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards. There was, Sir, in our Time, one Captain <hi>Fudge</hi> Commander of a Merchant-man, who upon his
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:50365:3"/>Return from a Voyage, how ill fraught ſoever his Ship was, always brought home his Owners a good Cargo of <hi>Lies,</hi> inſomuch that now aboard Ship the Sailors, when they hear a great <hi>Lye</hi> told, cry out, <hi>you fudge it.</hi> Now, Sir, I muſt give you to underſtand that this memorable Captain <hi>Fudge</hi> got diverſe and ſundry Sons, ſome for the Admiralty, ſome for the Navy, and ſome for Merchants Service; and this Author's Talent of <hi>Lying</hi> coming up to the Standard of the Sire, we can believe him to be no other than young <hi>Fudge</hi> of the Admiralty, and by his Multiplication of Lyes, may be admitted to Seniority, and take place as elder Brother.</p>
            <p>Young <hi>Fudge</hi> tells you, <hi>page</hi> 4. that the Party he ſcandalizes turned his back upon an Office wherein he was employ'd; but if he were reſtored to the Bread and Cheeſe he is fallen from, he dares anſwer for it that his Mouth would be ſtopt, and never open'd a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain on the like Subject: and this place, he ſays, <hi>pag.</hi> 6. was Clerk of the Cutting-houſe at 40 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> Do but mark the reaſon of the empty Creature; A Place of 40 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> did not ſtop his Mouth, and therefore the ſame place of 40 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> will ſtop his Mouth. Such conſequences as theſe, are the natural Product of the Brains employ'd in the Navy; where a wonder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Stupidity, join'd with a good ſtock of Impudence, never fails of Preferment. But I can aſſure him that Gentleman is ſo far from deſiring ſuch an Employ, or ſcandalizing himſelf by ſerving the Navy under ſuch an Adminiſtration, that he would not tell thoſe men his name for ſuch an Office.</p>
            <p>He tells us in the ſame Page, that he has <hi>a deſerved Poverty.</hi> Now it is no Crime nor Sin to be poor. But it is very hard for a man to be cheated of his
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:50365:3"/>Right, and then reflected upon for his Poverty. His Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verty indeed is deſerved on the account of his Services to this Government and his Country: Young <hi>Fudge</hi> is in the right on't here; for great care has been taken to keep thoſe down, that roſe moſt early in the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice of their Country. Theſe Reflections are but ſo many Arrows ſhot at themſelves; for there was never a man in that Office to which this Gentleman belong'd beſides himſelf, that ever ventur'd a Hair of his Head in the Service of his Country; yet at the ſame time, a parcel of poor inſignificant Mortals, as fooliſh as for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunate, enjoy'd places of 400 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> in that Office. Now the reaſon why this Gentleman took this mean Employ in that Office, was upon the account of an Uncle of his, then a Commiſſioner there, who brought him into that, in proſpect of another much better, likely then to be vacant; for which he had the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe of a certain Perſon, who deals ſo much in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion, that he cannot afford us any of his Morals, or ſo much as once be true to his word.</p>
            <p>This Obſervator <hi>fudges</hi> on, and tells you <hi>p.</hi> 5. That this Gentleman ſome years ago could not prove his Allegations before a Committee of the Houſe of Commons. How he came to have more ſenſe than the whole Houſe of Commons, I can't tell: for up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the report of that Affair to the Houſe, they were not of ſuch an Opinion. He tells you in the ſame Page, that he is Poet Laureat to the <hi>Calves-head Club:</hi> but if young <hi>Fudge</hi> were to be hang'd, or make good this Aſſertion, he would be in a fine Condition. In <hi>p.</hi> 6. he magnifies his Knowledg, by acquainting the world he has ſerved two Apprenticeſhips in the Naval School of <hi>England.</hi> I have known one that ſerved two Apprenticeſhips in a Univerſity, and yet as great a
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:50365:4"/>Fool as if he had never been there. He tells you a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bundance of Stories of his good Services, of his Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſty, <hi>&amp;c. p.</hi> 7. which we may believe to be e'en as true as what went before; for if it be true, he is a Nonſuch. He would make us believe, that he has not enrich'd himſelf by his Employment, and that he gets not one 4th part of what his Predeceſſors got be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore him. One Reaſon of this may be an Order put up in their Office, that no Officers thereunto belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſhould take any Bribes or Rewards; and I could wiſh another Article had been tack'd to that Order, <hi>viz.</hi> That the Commiſſioners ſhould receive no Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents of Prize Wines from the Commanders.</p>
            <p>Page 7th he ſays that he holds his Accuſer in the <hi>greateſt Contempt.</hi> Not ſo faſt good <hi>Fudge:</hi> the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſer you pretend, is a Gentleman born and bred; but you have skip'd to a high pitch of Inſolence, ſince you were <hi>Pip</hi>'s Footboy, and your good Lady Mother kept an Apple-ſtall in <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> with a little Net over it, leſt ſome unlucky Boy ſhould rob her of a Penny-worth of Apples and a halfpennyworth of Ginger-bread, and ſo break her at once. Tho you are skip'd up to Preferment, you muſt not undervalue men of Birth and Education, eſpecially one that has forgot more Learning than ever you were capable of remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bring.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Page</hi> 8. he tells you that this Perſon did ſometime ſince by Letter acquaint the Lords of the Admiralty with ſeveral Abuſes in the Navy, but eſpecially in the managing of the Victualling: their <hi>Lordſhips</hi> did thereupon ſignifie their deſire to ſpeak with him; but when he attended them, he excuſed himſelf by ſaying, That he had formerly laid thoſe Matters before other Perſons without Succeſs, and had little hopes of
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:50365:4"/>faring better from them. Now here is young <hi>Fudg</hi> again. For the Gentleman tells me that he never writ a Line to the Lords, before their Lordſhips ſent a Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter to him, requiring him to attend them. He came to the Office according to their Lordſhips Order, and enquiring of the Doorkeeper whether their Lordſhips were ſitting, the Door-keeper gave him a ſurly anſwer, and ſlap'd to the Door; however he knock'd again, when Mr. Door-keeper looking out, ſaluted him with a <hi>what does the Fellow want?</hi> At which the Gentleman gave him ſome hard Language, and told him their Lordſhips had ſent for him; but if they had nothing to ſay to him, he had nothing to ſay to them. Soon after this he was admitted to their Lordſhips, who indeed received him with a Civility anſwerable to their Characters, and gave him all the Reaſon in the World to imagine they were real in their Intentions to redreſs thoſe Grievances they were willing to be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted with. But the Secretary acquainted their Lordſhips, that this Gentleman had printed a ſcanda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous Libel, reflecting upon the late Commiſſioners, which was confirmed to their Lordſhips by another Scribe there, tho, I believe, neither of them ſaw that Gentleman's face before that time; which, together with ſome other ſcurvy Reflections, without any Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>primand from the Board, was diſcouragement enough for him not to lay any thing before them.</p>
            <p>He ſays, <hi>pag.</hi> 11. That this Gentleman, when the Board called before them the Commiſſioners for Victu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alling, upon a Complaint of Mr. <hi>Kelly,</hi> did not ſo far ſhew his Zeal to the Publick, as to appear face to face with thoſe Gentlemen. Truly 'tis no wonder he did not appear, when he knew nothing of the Buſineſs: Did their Lordſhips give him any notice? or did they
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:50365:5"/>order him to attend at that time? He prints a Letter from Mr. <hi>Burchett,</hi> pag. 10. to the Author of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>marks, which he ſays may ſufficiently teſtify he had an Opportunity offered him to bring to light what he knew upon Mr. <hi>Kelly</hi>'s hearing. Well ſaid young <hi>Fudge.</hi> The Letter to the Author is dated <hi>September</hi> 11. and Mr. <hi>Kelly</hi>'s hearing was the 6th of the ſame Month, five days before. This is Admiralty Reaſon all over. He ſays, at that time the Management of the Victualling was ſolemnly examined into, when Mr. <hi>Kelly</hi> ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moned about 50 Witneſſes, and but about a fifth part of them were called in and examined; this was a ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemn Hearing indeed. 'Tis true, he was no ſtranger to Mr. <hi>Kelly</hi>'s Complaint, but encourag'd him to lay it before that Board, in order to judg by their Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of a piece, what they would do with the whole.</p>
            <p>Upon this Hearing Captain <hi>Boult,</hi> the Purveyor for Corn, a Gentleman that knows more of the buſineſs of the Victualling than all the reſt concerned therein, was diſcharg'd from his Employment by their Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhips. I know not the Merits of Captain <hi>Boult</hi>'s Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge, but am fully aſſured that Miſmanagement lay at the door of another Perſon. However this Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man hearing it buzz'd about the Victualling Office, that Capt. <hi>Boult</hi> was diſcharged for accuſing one of the Commiſſioners, and knowing it to be the conſtant practice of the Victuallers to diſcharge all ſuch as made Complaints, thought it would be in vain to bring any more Perſons before their Lordſhips to teſtify any thing againſt the Commiſſioners, they being aſſur'd of a diſcharge by one Board or the other. But this Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man being unwilling to believe a thing upon a bare Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port or Surmiſe, went up to the Lords to know of them whether Captain <hi>Boult</hi> was diſcharged upon the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:50365:5"/>ſaid Account or no: But there being not a full Board, their Lordſhips declined giving him any anſwer to his Queſtion. And this is the true Account of the mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, however <hi>Fudg</hi> with his <hi>Billingſgate</hi> Rhetorick has been pleas'd to miſrepreſent it.</p>
            <p>Our empty-brain'd Author in the ſame Page, reflects on my Folly, in being concerned that the Lords of the Admiralty, upon receiving a Letter ſigned <hi>A. B.</hi> offering to make Diſcoveries, do cauſe to be inſerted in the Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zet the ſubject Matter of <hi>A. B</hi>'s Letter; and would be gladly informed, if two Letters ſhould come at the ſame time, ſigned <hi>A. B.</hi> to the very ſame purpoſe, and with the ſame Date, how he could ſatisfy either the one or the other <hi>A. B.</hi> their reſpective Letters were received, without hinting ſomething of the Contents of them. Certainly this cannot puzzle the boaſted Wiſdom of the Admiralty. If both Letters are ſigned <hi>A. B.</hi> and both of them contain the ſame matter; if one of the <hi>A. B</hi>'s appear, it may be ſufficient. And if after one <hi>A. B.</hi> has appear'd, if they are deſirous to hear what the other <hi>A. B.</hi> can ſay, 'tis but Gazetting again, and they'l be acquainted with both: or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, ſuppoſe their Lordſhips in one Advertiſement ſhould require both the <hi>A. B</hi>'s to appear, mayn't this be done without telling the ſubject matter of their Letters, which are both to the ſame purport?</p>
            <p>It is obſervable this Admiralty Officer, always in his Scribble, loads Complainers with the infamous name of <hi>Informers.</hi> Is this Character the mighty Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment they give to Complainers? 'Tis well they han't all their Throats cut, as one lately had at <hi>Portſmouth</hi> upon ſuch an Account; for thoſe who have ſerv'd their Country after this manner, have for the generality met with ſuch Treatment, or the recompenſe of ſtarving
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:50365:6"/>or loſing their Employments. It's a hard Caſe that ſuch as complain of Grievances, ſhould undergo the ſcandal of Informers, when ſuch as informed againſt Conventicles in the late Reigns, meet with ſuch Encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ragement in this, as a Journeyman Apothecary, a common Informer and Perſecutor, was made Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner of the Victualling. I could mention many more ſuch that have got good Employments, when ſuch as complain of Grievances get only the abuſive title of Informers from our Admiralty folk.</p>
            <p>Young <hi>Fudge</hi> ſays, <hi>page</hi> 12. of his Railery, That I am angry that the Fleet was not ſent from the <hi>Downs</hi> before the 15th of <hi>July</hi> laſt, in order to prevent a ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed Invaſion. <hi>And indeed,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I cannot wonder at his having ſo deep a ſenſe of an Invaſion, ſince (if I am not very much miſinform'd) his ſhewing an early good will to an Attempt of that kind in the late Reign, procu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red him ſuch Treatment as will always ſtick in his Stomach; and perhaps his meaning is, That then he ventur'd his Life for the preſervation of his Country:</hi> and that you may know what Invaſion he means, he tells you in the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin 'twas the Duke of <hi>Monmouths.</hi> I could tell you a pretty Story, were it convenient, concerning the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thods of deſtroying that unfortunate Duke; but as for the Invaſion I know nothing of it: when a People are robb'd of their Liberty, and are brought into perfect Slavery, they may come to the recovery of their Rights either by Land or by Water. And it is juſtifiable in any Perſon, tho never ſo obſcure, to head an armed Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany in defence of their Rights, much more a Perſon of that Duke's Quality, however unfortunate. That our Rights were then Invaded is beyond diſpute, when at that very time the late King was collecting the Cuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>toms and Exciſe without Act of Parliament. I make
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:50365:6"/>no queſtion but this Admiralty Tool, who in this Reign calls the Duke of <hi>Monmouth</hi>'s Diſembarkment an Invaſion, will in the next ſay as much of the Prince of <hi>Orange</hi>'s Deſcent; for I dare engage, like the Vicar of <hi>Bray,</hi> he'l hold in under all Governments, if fawn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſneaking, and lying will effect it. But prithee <hi>Fudg,</hi> according to the Doctrines of Paſſive Obedience and Non-Reſiſtance, the avowed Principles of thy Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; how can'ſt thou hold an Office under a Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment built upon the Ruins of thoſe Doctrines? but thy Conſcience is a State Weather-cock, turned about by the wind of any Revolution. The treatment I met with in the late Reigns was indeed ſevere enough, and none but an ill-bred Skipkennel would reflect upon a Man for his Misfortunes, which he has undergone with ſo much Reputation and Credit; nor are my Hardſhips under this Government much leſs, only with this difference, that I was as early to bring this King in as I was to drive the other out: nor am I alone in theſe Misfortunes, there are many beſide my ſelf that are diſcouraged by this Government, when many are en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled to buy themſelves into Offices with the Money they got for Pardons of the D. of <hi>Monmouth</hi>'s followers: and if the Recovery of our Rights be not juſtifiable, I ſhall with this Author conclude, that I did not then venture my Life for the preſervation of my Country.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Page</hi> 13. concerning the Fleet's lying in the <hi>Downs</hi> till <hi>July,</hi> he ſays,
<q rend="margDblQuotes">He cannot foreſee that they might not have been as ready from thence as any other place to prevent an Invaſion: For, ſuppoſing a Neighbour of ours had put to Sea with any ſuch De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign, and with a greater Strength, and that our Ships by being far Weſtward had been cut off from Succour, I would gladly know whether we had not
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:50365:7"/>then been in a hopeful Condition to defend our Country? For in ſuch a Caſe it would have been next to an impoſſibility to have ſent an additional Strength to their Relief, a greater Force being be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween them and ſuch Succour; ſo might they upon any Alarm, when in the <hi>Downs,</hi> either have gone from thence, and attack'd the Enemy with the Strength they had, or have continued there ſome time till more Ships could have joyn'd them from the River.</q>
            </p>
            <p>I can ſee no Reaſon why our Ships ſhould be too far Weſtward, or ſo far Eaſtward as the <hi>Downs,</hi> unleſs we purſue the old Methods of ſending them fartheſt out of the way, when they ſhould do us moſt Service. If a Neighbour of ours had a deſign to invade us, I think it a very improper Station to prevent it, to ride with our Ships at one end of his Country; when I ſtand in the middle of a Thing, I can ſee more of that Thing than if I ſtood at either end. Now in ſubmiſſion to the Admiralty Politicks, I ſuppoſe the <hi>Downs</hi> the worſt Station for our Shipping to obſtruct an Invaſion; in the firſt place it is a great way off any of the Enemies Ports, where their Ships of War are laid up; and then the Winds hanging Weſterly for at leaſt two thirds of the Year, the Enemy have an Opportunity of in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vading us when our Ships are Windbound; and they have all the Coaſt of <hi>England</hi> clear from the <hi>Downs</hi> to the <hi>Lands-end.</hi> I ſhould rather imagine St. <hi>Helens, Spithead,</hi> and <hi>Stokes-Bay,</hi> a proper Station for our Ships at ſuch a juncture. If we are not ſtrong enough in ſhipping, they are more readily ſupplied with an addi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tional force from <hi>Portſmouth,</hi> from whence they may be join'd in a few Hours. When our Author ſays, in the <hi>Downs</hi> they may be join'd from the River in a little
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:50365:7"/>time, he ſays he knows not what; ſuppoſe the Winds are contrary, it blows a Storm, or our great Ships are be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neapt. It's true, there are not ſo many Ships laid up at <hi>Portſmouth,</hi> as in <hi>Chatham</hi> River; but I hope they may be fitting out on ſuch an Occaſion, both at <hi>Chatham</hi> and <hi>Plymouth</hi> at the ſame time. We are in no danger from the Eaſtward, the Enemy has but few Ports that way, and all that Coaſt is a Lee-ſhoar above half the Year; and all the other Ports of our Enemy being to the Weſtward of St. <hi>Helens,</hi> if the Wind ſhould ſpring up to the Eaſtward, and bring any of the Enemies Ships from an Eaſtern Port, they cannot join their other Ships without obſtruction from our Fleet. But I ſhall go too far upon this Subject; for young <hi>Fudg,</hi> a little lower in this Page, tells me I am but a freſh Water Sailor, and conſequently can have no knowledg in Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>val Affairs: perhaps I have ſeen as much of the Sea as young <hi>Fudg</hi> himſelf; I think I ſaw more of it in the great Storm in <hi>February</hi> laſt, than ever I ſhall deſire to ſee again: yet ſuppoſe I am no Sailor, but a meer Land<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, why mayn't one Landman talk of Ships Stations, as well as another Landman appoint them?</p>
            <p>Now we muſt allow our <hi>Fudg</hi> to ſay ſomething in defence of an Office, in which he poſſeſſes ſo eminent a Poſt: he that will lye, will without doubt ſwear for his Maſters; he ſays the Royal Navy of <hi>England</hi> is not fallen to decay, but on the contrary,
<q rend="margDblQuotes">That in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of ſuch a Misfortune, our Royal Navy is at this time in a much better Condition than it was at the entrance into the War.</q> Thank you for nothing, good Sir, after ſo many Millions ſpent. I hope the Navy Officers han't embezeled all the Money appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for that Service; 'tis a hard caſe if we have not more Ships built, and our Dock-Yards fuller of Stores:
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:50365:8"/>but this is not the Queſtion, Are our Ships as well Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer'd? are they as well man'd, are they as well paid? have they as good a Diſcipline? Yes, he ſays,
<q rend="margDblQuotes">As to the Oeconomy and Diſcipline, there is no Man who is a proper Judg thereof, but will readily own very many Embeliſhments have been added thereunto by the Care and Pains of thoſe worthy Perſons who commanded both at Home and at Sea, ſince the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid War commenced.</q> The Embeliſhments added to the Diſcipline of the Navy, he inſerts in five Rules or Directions, <hi>p.</hi> 17. appointed to be obſerved in order to the returning to their Majeſties Service, ſuch Men as ſhall be put on ſhore ſick or hurt, from their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Ships. He tells you nothing how theſe Rules and Directions were obſerved, how the Complaints upon breach of theſe Directions have been redreſſed, not one word of this matter. Now to theſe five Rules and Directions of Navy Diſcipline, I ſhall at the end of this Paper add twelve more, which Mr. <hi>Dennis</hi> in his Paper preſents the World, under the name of Grievances; and in the mean time, Sir, ſhall diſcourſe ſomething concerning the Diſcipline of the Navy.</p>
            <p>The Sailors are the only People of the Engliſh Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, that are left to the diſcretionary Power of their Commanders, a Power indeed which belongs only to a Being which is always Wiſe, and ever Juſt. When Men execute ſuch a Power, it can be call'd no other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe than Arbitrary, for all Men are born to ſome Rights, and thoſe Rights are ſecured to them by ſome Laws. Now to take away from them thoſe Rights in defiance of thoſe Laws, is an action in it ſelf Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitrary. No Court of Juſtice in <hi>England</hi> can give a Sentence ſo definitive, that the Defendant ſhall have no Appeal to any other Court. If I am caſt at Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:50365:8"/>Law, I can appeal to Chancery; if in Chancery I have a Decree againſt me, which I eſteem extrajudi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial, I can appeal to the higheſt Court of Parliament: but the poor Sailors Caſe comes not under the Cogni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſance of any of our Courts, they are oppreſs'd by the Diſcretionary Power of their Commanders, without any equitable Relief, according to the Conſtitution of their Country. I ſhall here therefore endeavour to ſhow that the Diſcipline of our Navy has been directly contrary to our Conſtitution, and then leave any one to judg of that Diſcipline, whether it has not been matter of juſt Complaint, and an abominable Abuſe up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Sailors.</p>
            <p>The 29th Chapter of <hi>Magna Charta</hi> ſays, <hi rend="blackletterType">No Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man ſhall be taken or Impriſoned, or be diſſeized of his Freehold, or Liberties, or Free Cuſtoms, or be Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>law'd or Exiled, or any otherwiſe deſtroyed; nor We will not paſs upon him, nor condemn him, but by lawful Iudgment of his Peers, or by the Law of the Land.</hi> Theſe words <hi>per Legem Terrae,</hi> in the end of this Chapter, do refer to all the precedent matter con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained in it. Now I give any one leave to judg whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Impreſſing Seamen for the Service, be not a violation of <hi>Magna Charta,</hi> when Men are <hi>taken</hi> and <hi>impriſoned</hi> a Shipboard ſix or ſeven Years together. To ſay we are a free People when any of us are in effectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Slavery, is meer Nonſenſe; for the ſame Power that deprives one part of the People of their Liberty, may enſlave the whole People. And yet how many Preſs-Warrants have we had granted from the Admiralty to Men that are no Officers? For none are ſuch, but thoſe that are under the Cognizance of the Laws of the Land: Where do our Laws make mention of a Preſs<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſter? Whom do our Laws commiſſionate to conſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:50365:9"/>ſuch Officers? Now when a Freeman is taken and impriſoned by an Officer not known to our Laws, ſuch an Act is a downright Piracy upon the Liberty of the People.</p>
            <p>If they object, That without this Diſcipline the Ships of War cannot be mann'd for the ſecurity of the Realm: if it be Neceſſary, make it Legal; we had as good loſe our Country, as loſe our Rights. But how have Navys been ſupply'd with Men in former Ages? When the Nation's Service was accounted the beſt at Sea, and Men made Intereſt to get before the Maſt; this proceeded from the good Diſcipline of thoſe times, the good Uſage of the Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men by their Commanders; they were not then poi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon'd with bad Proviſions, Peaſe-Bread, and ſtinking Beef and Pork; they were not then kept out of their Pay by Q's and R's: Such Men as General <hi>Blake,</hi> the Earl of <hi>Sandwich, Dean, Lawſon, Bourn, Minns,</hi> &amp;c. were familiar with their Sailors, and inſtead of calling them damn'd Dogs, or Sons of Whores, call'd 'em Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren. The Abuſes of Seamen in this point, during this War, have been very conſiderable, but without Redreſs, as their other Grievances have; and ſome have been commiſſionated in this Affair, too big for me to mention, and have received Salaries for this piece of Service, tho I could never hear of any Service they did, ſave only a Cuſtomer's impreſſing a great many Maſters of Ships at <hi>Brighthelmſtone.</hi> They were not only Seamen they preſs'd, but many times Landmen, when the preſs Smacks coming into ſmall Creeks took ſuch Men away, and carrying them 40 or 50 Miles from their own homes, have left them to beg their way to their own Country; many thus have had their Limbs ſtarv'd by lying upon the Ballaſt, being
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:50365:9" rendition="simple:additions"/>unaccuſtomed to ſuch hardſhips; and when any of the Landmen thus preſſed have been diſcharged, they have paid 12 <hi>d. per</hi> day to the Maſter of the Smack for Diet, and no doubt but the King paid near as much. Now I perceive the main Reaſon of want of men, is our want of good Commanders. Capt. <hi>Jumper,</hi> nor any of thoſe Commanders during the War that uſed their men honeſtly and civilly, ever wanted their Comple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of men: But our Beau Commanders, the Sir <hi>Courtlys</hi> of the Sea, if they were forced to man their Ships upon their own Credit and Reputation amongſt the Sailors, would not be able to bring them from the River to the <hi>Downs</hi> in a twelve Month. And to keep theſe Creatures in Commiſſion, we muſt it ſeems make a rent in our Conſtitution.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>No man ſhall be diſſeiſed,</hi> i. e. put out of <hi>Seiſin,</hi> or diſpoſſeſſed of his Freehold, <hi>i. e.</hi> Lands or Livelyhood, Liberties or Free Cuſtoms, which belong to him as his free Birth-right. Now to ſay that a Seaman has not as good a Right as any to the Free Cuſtoms, Franchiſes, and Liberties of the Country he is born in, is very abſurd. If a Landman has a liberty to go on Foot, or Horſeback, or by Coach, to follow that Employ whereby he gets his livelyhood; has not a Seaman the ſame Right, to ſail in what Ship and to what Port he pleaſes?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>No man ſhall be outlaw'd,</hi> made an <hi>Exlex, i. e.</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barred of the Benefit of the Law of the Land, unleſs it be done according to Law. Now according to the Diſcipline of the Navy, are not all our Sailors Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laws, and deprived of the Benefit of the Law, when they are not their own men, but liable to be taken into Cuſtody, and deprived of their Liberty by every rapacious Preſs-maſter?</p>
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:50365:10"/>
            <p>
               <hi>No man ſhall be exiled,</hi> baniſhed from the Place of his Nativity. <hi>Nemo perdet Patriam.</hi> By the Laws of our Land, no man can be baniſhed from his Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Country, but upon two Accounts. 1ſt. Either by the Power or Authority of Parliament; or 2dly. In caſe of Abjuration for Felony by the Common Law. The King himſelf cannot ſend any Subject of <hi>England</hi> againſt his Will to ſerve him out of this Realm, ſo that he ſhould be an Exile, and that he ſhould <hi>perdere Patriam.</hi> But it ſeems the Officers of the Navy have a greater Power than the King, who can force <hi>Freemen</hi> from their Country, and ſend them to ſerve in the moſt remote Regions of the World.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>No man ſhall be deſtroyed (Deſtruere id eſt quod prius ſtructum &amp; factum fuit, penitus Evertere &amp; Deſtruere)</hi> unleſs by a Legal Verdict. By deſtroying is meant forejudging of Life and Limb, or putting to Torture or Death; every oppreſſion againſt Law by colour of any uſurped Authority, being a kind of Deſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. Now to apply this to the Diſcipline of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy. What dee' think of whipping our Seamen at the Gears, and then baſting their flea'd Backs with as many Canns of Pickle as the Commander by his diſcretiona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Power pleaſes to order? Are not our Ships thus be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come meer <hi>Bridewells,</hi> and our Sailors as bad or worſe than Gally Slaves? nay, I have known a Boy of 2 or 3 and twenty years of age laſh'd to a Gun and whipt, a puniſhment given to the youngeſt Boys on board Ship. Had our Commanders any Religion, our Seamen might ſtand in fear of the Inquiſition. If a ſtop be not put to their Barbarous and Inhumane Cruelties, they'l in time borrow the Rack from the <hi>French,</hi> and the Boot and Thumb Screws from the <hi>Scots.</hi> Can you blame the Sailors for running from ſuch Tortures, and ſhall they
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:50365:10"/>be puniſht for complaining of their Miſeries. 'Tis this, Sir, that daſtardizes and effeminates the noble Spirits of your Seamen: 'Tis this makes them deſert the Service of their Country: 'Tis this peoples Colonys of Pirates abroad: And 'tis this will in time be the Ruin of the moſt Glorious Navy of the Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe. Nor are Pecuniary Mulcts a leſs Crime. How this came to be a part of the Diſcipline of the Navy, I can't tell; but when men govern by their Will, and not by Law, we muſt every day expect new pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhments. But if it's reaſonable that the Sailors ſhould be puniſht after this manner, is it not as reaſonable that the Mulct ſhould be anſwerable to the Crime? If a Sailor be abſent from his Ship a Week, is not that Week's pay ſufficient to be ſtopt for that Week's Crime? The Fines in our Courts of Juſtice are laid according to the Worth of the Criminal, exorbitant Fines having in all Ages been eſteemed extrajudicial: no man can be fin'd more than he is capable of paying; and to fine a Perſon to the full Value of his Eſtate, is giving away all a man has been gathering for many Years for one Piccadillo.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>By lawful Judgment of his Peers, and by the Law of the Land.</hi> Peers, that is his Equals, men of the ſame Rank and Quality with himſelf. But the Sailors are not try'd after this manner, the ſame Perſon is Accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſer, Judg and Jury: they have no Indictment, no Jury empannel'd, no Counſel to plead for them; ſtrip they muſt, and to the Gears; the Cat of nine-Tails, and the Pickle Cann muſt be exerciſed upon the Back, as long as the Whipping-Tom upon the Quarter Deck is pleas'd with the ſport. 'Tis pity young <hi>Fudge's</hi> dear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly beloved Friend <hi>Jefferies</hi> is dead; he exercis'd his Talent ſo well in the late Reign in the <hi>Weſt,</hi> that he
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:50365:11"/>would have made an excellent Navy Officer now. They are to be try'd too by the Law of the Land, <hi>i. e.</hi> by due Proceſs of Law, for ſo the words are ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſly expounded by the Stat. of 37 <hi>Ed.</hi> 3. Chap. 8. But inſtead of this Trial, they are puniſht by the Law of the Admiralty without any Trial at all. So that the poor Tarrs are a ſort of People that have no Right at all to any thing but ill Uſage and barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous unmanly Puniſhments; Puniſhments that are ſuperior to Death it ſelf, becauſe ignominious and ſhameful; <hi>malim mori quam vapulari.</hi> But our Navy Officers, like the <hi>Sicilian</hi> Tyrants, employ their Brains more in contriving new ſorts of Puniſhments, than in finding out good and wholeſom Laws to maintain a Diſcipline in the Navy.</p>
            <p>Thus, Sir, I have given you a ſhort view of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conſiſtence of the Navy Diſcipline with the funda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mental Laws of our Realm; a Diſcipline not only contrary to the Laws of our Country, but even to the Laws of Nature, and the practice of the moſt un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>civilized part of the world. And upon the whole I muſt conclude, that they being warranted by no Law in the Execution of theſe Severities, have aſſumed to, and veſted themſelves with a Legiſlative Power, a Power I ſhall never own to be lodged any where but in Parliament. But if the People of <hi>England</hi> are ſo far willing to part with their Conſtitution, as to ſuffer the Navy Officers to make Laws penal, 'een let 'em allow the Lords of the Treaſury Power to raiſe Mony, and then our Buſineſs is brought into a very narrow Compaſs; 'twill be a great eaſe to you Members of Parliament, you may retire into the Country, walk over your pleaſant Fields, and ſit under your own Vines; but I can tell you in a ſhort time who'l eat
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:50365:11"/>your Grapes. Pray, Sir, do but call to mind the days of old, the years of your Forefathers; look into the Chronicles of former Ages: did any of your worthy Progenitors ſuffer their Rights thus to be invaded by men that are their Servants, and receive their Pay? Have they not left you Copies of your Freedom, ſealed with their own blood? What Hazards have they run? what Dangers have they attempted? what Battels have they fought to ſecure to Poſterity thoſe Liberties they valued before their Lives? Are not our Liberties the ſame? Has envious Time devoured any part of them? Are they leſs amiable becauſe they are old? Did they bring Kings to diſtreſs, ſhatter Crowns, and humble Tyrannical Princes, who inva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded their Birth-rights? And will you ſuffer your Freedoms, your Antient Conſtitution thus to be rent and torn by men of inferior Quality? Whom your Forefathers would have impeached in the name of the good People of <hi>England,</hi> and made them anſwer for aſſuming to themſelves a Legiſlative Power. If you read an excellent Book lately publiſhed, entituled, <hi>A Vindication of Magna Charta,</hi> you'l there ſee how valuable thoſe Rights were, and what Toil and La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour our Forefathers underwent to keep them entire, and tranſmit them to Poſterity.</p>
            <p>I ſhall in the next place prove, that the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners for executing the Office of Lord High Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miral of <hi>England</hi> during the War, have aſſumed to themſelves a Diſpenſing Power.</p>
            <p>By an Act, <hi>Anno Gulielmi &amp; Mariae</hi> 4 <hi>to, &amp;</hi> 5 <hi>to.</hi> entituled, <hi>An Act for continuing the Acts for prohibit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all Trade and Commerce with</hi> France, <hi>and for the Encouragement of Privateers,</hi> p. 505. it is enacted,
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:50365:12"/>
               <q rend="margDblQuotes">That if any Captain or Officer, or any other Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon by his Command or Direction, or any Seaman, or Souldier, or other Perſon ſerving in their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſtys Navy, or in any Privateer, ſhall take to him or themſelves, or imbezle any Mony, Plate, Goods, Lading or Tackle, or any things upon, or above the Gun Deck, or any other part or place whatſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, in any Ship taken or ſeized on for Prize, or retaken from the Enemy, the party offending ſhall loſe and forfeit the Shares, Proportions and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards to him allowed by this Act. And alſo in caſe ſuch Perſon be an Officer, he ſhall forfeit the Sum of five hundred Pounds; and ſuch Officer ſhall be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>capable of any Office or Employment under their Majeſtys during the ſpace of ſeven Years.</q>
            </p>
            <p>Many Commanders of Ships, guilty of embezling Prize Goods, and of running of Wines, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to Law, have notwithſtanding this been either continued or reſtored to their Commands. If your Honourable Houſe pleaſes to ſend for a Liſt of ſuch Commanders as have been diſcharged, and after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards reſtored to their Commands, and examine in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the merits of the Cauſe for which they were diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged, you will find this a manifeſt Truth. To have the Kings ſhips become Owlers, is far worſe: as lately a parcel of Wool was ſeized on board the <hi>Iſabella</hi> Yacht, that has the ſtation betwixt <hi>Southampton</hi> and <hi>Jerſey.</hi> I know not how her Pilot Mr. <hi>Peter de St. Croix</hi> (whom I have known much averſe to things of that nature) was prevailed on to take the Matter upon himſelf; But this I know very well, that if your Honourable Houſe would enquire into this ſingle thing, it would be of great Advantage. I am ſure the Judges took the Caſe right enough, whatever the Opinion
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:50365:12"/>of the Admiralty might be concerning it. If a Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant makes a miſtake in entring of Goods, the King's Officers are ſharp enough upon him; but when Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers themſelves, or Commanders of the Navy are guilty of theſe Crimes, they have Friends to bring them off, tho contrary to the Laws of the Land.</p>
            <p>Now, Sir, for theſe very Practices, for the Diſpenſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with Laws, did we depoſe the late King <hi>James:</hi> Upon this Account had this very Government its Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing. And ſhall we ſuffer Men in Commiſſion under the Government, not only to make new Laws, but diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>penſe with old ones? Their Power is indeed very great, who can make Laws, inflicting Puniſhments upon others, when no Laws are binding upon them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves. They are ſelf-holders of the Admiralty, ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported by an uncontroulable Power, and Soveraign Will. What a miſerable Condition are thoſe Men in, that are under the Command of ſuch whoſe unlimited Rage always roars, and where Laws are always ſilent? This is the Oeconomy of the ſavage Beaſts of the Earth, and thus our Offices become meer Deſerts.</p>
            <p>I ſhall next ſhow you how theſe makers of new Laws are Repealers of the old, good, and wholeſom Practices and Cuſtoms of the Navy. Their <hi>Fudge</hi> tells you of the Embeliſhments they have added, but not of the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naments they have taken away. It has been the conſtant practice of the Admiralty in the days of yore, to prefer Men according to their Merit and Demeanour on Ship<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>board: the Navy of <hi>England</hi> was in thoſe times a School, wherein the young Gentlemen of the Nation were educated and inſtructed in the Military Arts of the Sea, and became greatly ſerviceable to their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try. Theſe Men being deſcended from generous Stocks, valued their Reputation, and ſcorn'd to do any thing
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:50365:13"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:50365:13"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:50365:14"/>that might blot or ſtain their Pedigree. The Sailors of the Navy had then better Treatment, abuſes being be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neath the Character of Gentlemen: Cruelties and Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barities are inconſiſtent with the nature of generous and noble Spirits; Whipping and Pickling was then a Puniſhment unknown. Cruelty and Cowardice are things inſeparable, and practiſed only by Men of a ſervil Education. If a Foot-boy or Page be made a Commander, he remembers the Flaps of the Cook<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maids Diſhclout, the Baſting and Caning of his Maſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter's Steward; and now it comes to his turn to domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neer, he tyrannizes with a reſiſtleſs Fury. Thoſe Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen that were Reformades, or King's Letter-men, were ſure of being Lieutenants in former times, and as ſure of being Captains in their turn; no Foot-boys or Pages then skip'd over their Heads. But now you may find Lieutenants of many Years ſtanding in the Navy, while Maſters of Merchant-men, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> are made Commanders of 3d Rates, a Poſt in former Ages not beneath the Dignity of Noblemen; as for inſtance, the Earl of <hi>Oſſory</hi> in the <hi>Reſolution,</hi> and the Lord <hi>Mulgrave</hi> in the <hi>Royal Katherine.</hi> Our Ships were then throng'd with Noblemen, their Sons, and the Sons of our Gentry. But how many of Quality have ſerved in the Fleet during this War? And is not the loſs of Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pline the apparent Cauſe thereof? For 'tis contrary to the very being of generous Spirits to ſerve under the Command of the Riffraff of their Country, and to do Homage to Men of more inferior Qualities than their Servants. And what encouragement is thus given to thoſe Gentlemen that have ſerved a long time in the Navy as Lieutenants or otherwiſe, when thoſe that never ſerved the King one hour are preferred over their Heads? It is farther obſervable, that the Maſters of
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:50365:14" rendition="simple:additions"/>ſuch Merchant-ſhips as have been hired into the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice during the War, by the Intereſt of the Owners, have been made Commanders of them, to the Diſcou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ragement of ſuch as have ſerved in the Navy: ſuch Commanders in an Engagement were more likely to ſave the Merchantſhips from blows than hazard them in the King's Service. But for all this they boaſt of the Diſcipline of the Navy, as a thing excelling that of former Ages, in defiance to publick Opinion, and the Reſults of the mature Debates of the Wiſdom of the Nation. Yet upon this Account have the Enemies of the Government no occaſion to reflect upon it, no more than the Husbandman is to be blamed for the nu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merous quantities of Weeds that ſpring up among his Wheat. The King never gave his Commiſſion to the Officers of the Navy to oppreſs his Subjects, to ſilence old Laws, and enact new Ones. And 'tis much to be feared, methods are taken to prevent the Complaints and Cries of the Subject from reaching his Majeſties Ears; otherwiſe we cannot imagine a Prince that has experienced ſo much of their tender Affection, of their Bravery in War, and the generous Supplies they have given him to preſerve his Perſon and Government, would ſuffer them to languiſh under ſuch intolerable and illegal Evils. If they had Commiſſions granted upon ſuch an Account, we ſhould know whereabouts we are. Yet tho ſuch Commiſſions, being out of the Verge of the Executive Power, are to be accounted for, the Perſons executing them are not excuſable, however it fared with the Miniſters of the late King <hi>James.</hi> But we have no room for Imaginations of this kind un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der this Government. And I may farther add, that were his Majeſty truly ſenſible of the Condition of his Sailors, he would not ſuffer ſuch Abuſes upon them;
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:50365:15"/>he would not withhold from them their Wages, upon the Account of pretended and illegal Forfeitures: his wonted and manifeſt Clemency muſt create in us bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Thoughts, than that he who has pardon'd Aſſaſſins, ſuch as have conſpired to take away his Life, that has eaſed <hi>Newgate</hi> ſo often of its burden of Criminals of all ſorts, by Acts of Grace and Free Pardons, will ſuffer his Sailors to loſe their Pay, and ſtarve for inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent Crimes, without extending his Mercy towards them.</p>
            <p>Now, Sir, having given you a true account of the nature of our Naval Diſcipline, I ſhall ſpend a little more time in conſidering what young <hi>Fudge,</hi> the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miralty Author, has to ſay for his Maſters. <hi>P.</hi> 21. he ſays,
<q rend="margDblQuotes">Care has been always taken to do Juſtice to the Sailors; for when any one produced reaſonable Teſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timonials that he did not deſignedly deſert the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, but after Recovery endeavoured to return to his proper Ship, if in the way, or entred himſelf in any other Ship or Veſſel within reach, or that he was Impreſſed when endeavouring ſo to do, the Q has been taken off, and he reſtored to his Pay.</q> Now the queſtion is, what thoſe reaſonable Teſtimonials are; a few Guineas to young <hi>Fudge,</hi> I believe as good a Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monial as can be. But what do Teſtimonials, Certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficates, or things of that nature ſignify, if they won't receive them?</p>
            <p>He tells you, <hi>p.</hi> 21.
<q rend="margDblQuotes">That the Lords of the Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ralty did in leſs than ſix months time, relieve at leaſt 750 of the ſeventeen hundred Perſons that made Application.</q> How long was it before their Cauſe was heard? How long had their Petitions lain at the Board? It was near ſix months before the ſeven hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:50365:15"/>and fifty were relieved; and before the ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen hundred can be relieved, it will make it up eighteen months, or thereabouts. Now ſuppoſe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they were heard, their Petitions lay but 6 Months, this added to the 18 Months makes two Years; and ſuppoſe ſome of theſe Men have but ſix or twelve Months pay due to them, is it worth while to attend two Years to ſollicite for ſix Months Wages, which they are not certain of getting at the two Years end?</p>
            <p>He tells us, <hi>pag.</hi> 22.
<q rend="margDblQuotes">That the Seamen have been much wanting to themſelves and Families, as to forfeit their Pay by turning their Back upon their Duty.</q> When Men have been five or ſix Years in the Service without one penny of Wages, can you blame them? Who would not turn their Backs upon ſuch a Service? Are a Servant's Wages forfeited, becauſe he deſerts his Maſter's Service? Are not his Wages as recoverable by Law, as they were before he deſerted? 'Tis much to be feared that Men are thus kept out of their Pay, on purpoſe to make them deſert the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; for the Money for their Service is without doubt brought into the Pay Office, and the longer it lies there, the better it is for the Caſhiers: The very Intereſt thereof comes to ſomething; they may lend it the Government at 8 <hi>per Cent.</hi> I rather think the Sailors are more wanting to themſelves and Familys, by entering into the Service, than by leaving it: For in a Merchant-man they might meet with good Uſage and good Pay. And ſuppoſe the major part of the Sailors of the Engliſh Navy are impreſſed into the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice, muſt they be made Priſoners, and loſe their due for giving themſelves that Liberty, wherein the Laws of their Country, of God and Nature have ſet them free? I believe if young <hi>Fudg</hi> were to be whipt and
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:50365:16"/>pickl'd for 22 <hi>i.</hi> 6 <hi>d. per menſem,</hi> he would near hand de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſert the Service. Theſe Men do not run away from their Pay, but they run away becauſe they are not paid; but young <hi>Fudg</hi> is like the Fellow that beat his Dog till he ſtank, and then beat him for ſtinking.</p>
            <p>Now our Naval Politicks are quite ſpent, the whole Store of Admiralty ſenſe and railery is at an end: for <hi>Fudg</hi> repeats in <hi>pag.</hi> 23. the very ſame dull ſtuff that preceded in <hi>page</hi> 22. And upon the whole, Sir, have you not here a very fine Account of the Management of your Navy? This is an entire Syſtem of our Naval Politicks, written no doubt <hi>permiſſu &amp; emendationibus Superiorum.</hi> If we are to be invaded, you ſee our Ships Stations at that time muſt be in the <hi>Downs;</hi> this is but a ſample of their wonderful Sagacity, and what we muſt expect from their Conduct. And as for their Naval Diſcipline, I hope I have ſet you right in that Point; for tho I muſt needs acknowledg a Diſcipline in the Navy to be very neceſſary, yet there's differ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence betwixt ſtaring and ſtark mad. Men ought to be kept to their Duty, but not by ſuch ſevere and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>humane Methods as ſhall frighten them from the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice. By ſuch a Diſcipline we ſhall have no Men to exerciſe our Diſcipline upon, but ſhall act like the wiſe Commander, who ſunk his Ship to drown the Rats. By ſuch a Diſcipline we ſhall not only bring upon us the Curſes of the Sailors, but the Curſes of God Almighty, who hears the Cries of the Oppreſſed, and puniſhes King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doms for ſuch acts of Violence. Theſe Men that impoſe ſuch ſtrict Diſcipline on others, have none among them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves. If their Attendance at their reſpective Offices were enquired into, you will find as much reaſon to prick them Run, as the poor Sailors. Some of them can be abſent three or four Months together, and yet
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:50365:16"/>receive their Pay without any Q or R. We are not, you know, Sir, in Debt, and therefore can allow one of the Victuallers to look after his Oxen in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try at Summer, to ſell them a good pennyworth to the King at Winter. Bring but our Sailors upon the ſame foot with the Commiſſioners of the Navy, and Victualling; let their Ships be double mann'd, as thoſe Offices are double Commiſſioner'd, that one half may do Duty while the t'other half is abſent, and we'll no more complain of Q's and R's.</p>
            <p>I am ſure, Sir, I have not miſpent my Time, if theſe few Pages prove any ways ſerviceable to the common good of my Country: Tho indeed I ſhould have taken no notice of my trifling railing Obſervator, had I not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore reſolved to publiſh my Thoughts on the Diſcipline of the Navy. How conſiderable ſoever he may think himſelf, becauſe he occupies an immerited Office un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Government, he thinks himſelf unanſwerable, as you may ſee in the very firſt Paragraph of his Book, with which I ſhall conclude; ſays he,
<q rend="margDblQuotes">It might have been reaſonably believed, that the Author of a late Pamphlet, relating to Miſmanagements in the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy, would have left of Scribling, ſince the Anſwer to his laſt Year's Politicks left him ſo little Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation.</q> Now you muſt know, Sir, that young <hi>Fudg</hi> laſt Year printed an Anſwer to my <hi>State of the Navy:</hi> It contain'd about as much ſtuff as a halfpenny Ballad, tho not half ſo much ſenſe. But becauſe no body took any notice of him, he thought every Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy acquieſc'd with his Opinion, and that his Nonſenſe paſs'd as current with Mankind, as a Seaman's Ticket does for 7 <hi>s.</hi> and 6 <hi>d.</hi> in the Pound. It is impoſſible for a Man that has no Reputation to blaſt the Credit of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother in the Opinion of good and juſt Men, the only
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:50365:17"/>Perſons whoſe Favour Ieſteem; and I can aſſure young <hi>Fudg,</hi> if he adds a dung Cart full of Lies to the Wheel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barrow he has fill'd already, I ſhould not ſtain my Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation to rake in his Dirt. The reproaches of Fools, the ſcandals of the Rabble, are no cauſe of Reſentment to Men that know better how to employ their Thoughts; nor am I any more concerned at things of this nature, than the Moon, who keeps on her ſteady and conſtant Courſe, while all the little Dogs in the Pariſh are barking at her.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="grievances">
            <div n="1" type="grievance">
               <head>The Firſt Grievance is Queries.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>THE Nature and Effect of thoſe Queries are, That every Man ſet on Shoar ſick, and not returning to his proper Ship or ſome other in one Month, or immediately after diſcharg'd from ſick Quarters, thereby forfeits his Wages.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="grievance">
               <head>The Second Grievance is R's.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>And thoſe</hi> R's <hi>have of late been ſtrenuouſly obſerved, if not improved to the Seaman's Prejudice. The Nature or Effect of thoſe</hi> R's <hi>as now practiſed, is, That the Perſons who by accident or otherwiſe, do leave or are left by their proper Ships, are by thoſe</hi> R's <hi>noted to be Run, and forfeit all the Wages due to them, not only in the Ships they leave, but in all former Ships as far as the ſame is unpaid, notwithſtanding Tickets long before delivered them for their former ſervice; by what new Rules or Orders this is practis'd I cannot ſay, but am well aſſur'd 'tis contrary to the former Practice and Rules of the Navy.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="grievance">
               <head>The Third Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The deferring or non-payment of the Wages of ſuch as are dead or abſent, notwithſtanding others have attended with ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient Power to receive the ſame, and no colour of Objection, and thoſe to whom it's due ready to periſh for want: to ſuch there are ſeveral</hi> 100000 l. <hi>now due and in Arrears, which ſhould have been long ſince paid.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="grievance">
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:50365:17"/>
               <head>The Fourth Grievance is, the unuſual and irregular man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of Payment lately practiſed, <hi>viz.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Some Ships that have three or four Years Pay due, have been paid only ten or twelve Months, the latter time, and the former left unpaid upon account of their Companies being turned over in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to other Ships.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2dly. <hi>Some Ships paid for the whole time, yet many People left unpaid.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="grievance">
               <head>The Fifth Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Turning Men over from Ship to Ship, lending them, and bearing them by Liſt, that they know not in what Ship, nor by what means they may obtain their Wages.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="grievance">
               <head>The Sixth Grievance is the Alteration of Officers Qualities.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>By this their Wages have been retrenched, ſome from</hi> 3l. <hi>to</hi> 36 s. <hi>others from</hi> 36 <hi>to</hi> 23 s. &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="grievance">
               <head>The Seventh Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Non-payment of Powers (or Letters of Attorney) made to Officers; that is, if any Officer's Father, Brother, Relation, or any other Friend hath ſerved in the Navy, and hath made a Letter of Attorney to ſuch Officer to receive the Wages, he is de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nied Payment of the ſame.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="grievance">
               <head>The Eighth (tho not a poſitive) Grievance;</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Yet as Matter worthy Conſideration, I ſhall hint ſomething touching the ſmallneſs of the able Seaman's Pay, and would not omit the Gunners, Boatſwains, and Carpenters herein.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>As for the able Seamans Pay, it is</hi> 24 s. per <hi>Month, the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duction from the Regiſtred Seamen</hi> 1 s. <hi>and from thoſe that are not Regiſtred</hi> 1 s. 6d. per <hi>Month, ſo that their Pay is but</hi> 22 s. <hi>and</hi> 6 d. <hi>The Warrant-Officers before-mentioned, have Pay according to the reſpective Rates they are in.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="grievance">
               <head>The Ninth Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Difficulty of obtaining His Majeſty's gracious Bounty allowed the Widows and Children of ſuch as are ſlain in His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty's Service, and the Monies due for the Clothes of ſuch as die; which Clothes are generally ſold at the Maſt; ſuch Seamens Families and Relations being at a diſtance, and not knowing where to find the proper Officers to ſign ſuch Certificates as re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:50365:18" rendition="simple:additions"/>for the Payment of ſuch Bounty and Clothe-Money, it hath been long delayed, and often-times intirely loſt.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="grievance">
               <head>The Tenth Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Non-payment of the Regiſter'd Seamen, (not to inſiſt on</hi> 40 s. per Annum <hi>hitherto unpaid) I ſhall only mention the Caſe of the Widows, Friends, and Relations of ſuch as have died in the Service, with reſpect to their Wages.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>Such as die on Voyages to</hi> Holland, France, <hi>the</hi> Narrow-Seas, &amp;c. <hi>their Wages are refuſed to be paid according to the Act, it being alledged that ſuch are not Foreign Voyages.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>Such as have been bound out on Foreign Voyages, and died be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Ships departure from</hi> England, <hi>their Wages are alſo refuſed.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>Such as have been on Foreign Voyages ſo accounted, and in ſuch Voyages have contracted Sickneſs, whereof they have died im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediately after the Ships Return to</hi> England; <hi>their Wages are alſo refuſed, as not intended by the ſaid Act to be paid.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>Such as have gone out in one Ship, and ſerved a conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble time in her, and afterwards turned over into another, and there in a few Months died; the Widows of ſuch are paid for the Ships only wherein they died, and not for the former.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi>Such Commiſſion and Warrant Officers as are Regiſter'd who die on Foreign Voyages, their Wages are refuſed, as not inten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to be paid by the ſaid Act.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="11" type="grievance">
               <head>The Eleventh Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The Government and Diſcipline uſed in the Navy; but there being already good and wholeſom Laws provided, both for ſuppreſſing Vice, and encouraging Virtue, I have little to ſay, only that the Epidemical abounding of Vice and Debauchery through the whole Fleet, too evident<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly demonſtrates the Neglect, if not the Contempt of the ſaid Laws: And it would be well if the Practice and Example of ſuperior Officers did not ſo much contribute to the ſame; and whether this (with a ſor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>did and ſlaviſh Puniſhment, viz.</hi> Whipping <hi>and</hi> Pickling, <hi>much us'd of late, and that on frivolous Occaſions) do not tend to the daſtardizing of the Spirits of our Engliſh Seamen, and the animating and emboldening our Enemies, and conſequently to the Nations Prejudice, 'twill do well to conſider; and if found to be ſo, to redreſs the ſame.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="12" type="grievance">
               <head>The Twelfth Grievance is,</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>The fraudulent Dealing of many that pretend to ſolicite Buſineſs, and receive Wages in the Navy, by which the Seamen are alſo prejudiced; but the Particulars hereof being too long to inſert herein, ſhall at preſent omit the ſame.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="erratum">
            <p>
               <hi>Errat.</hi> Page 16. line 15. for <hi>deſtruere</hi> read <hi>obruere.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
